SAMUEL JACOBO GARAVITO SEGURA

APPLYCATION

Mathematician
PYTHON/RPA Developer
Back-end developer

PERSONAL INFO

Name: Samuel Jacobo Garavito Segura.

I.D. 1192798537.

Date of Birth: 06/01/2001.

Place of Birth: Bogotá D.C. Colombia.

Marital Status: Single.

Address: 69N avenue # 63C - 33

Phone: +57 3208631814. E-Mail: saaravito@unal.edu.co.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-

jacobo-garavito-segura-mathpy/

GitHub: https://github.com/SgaravitoWp

PROFILE

Mathematics student with operational experience working as a Python/RPA developer and debugger in charge of finding solutions for data extraction and manipulation. Experience in API design, writing and implementation with Flask and FastAPI. Experience in IT automation for Linux systems finding opportunities for automation within software processes, identify bugs and quality issues in development. Proficiency in Python (2 years) with different frameworks using object-oriented programming together with control versioning tools such as Git and Github.

LANGUAGES

Spanish English Native Speaker Fluent (C1 level)

WORK EXPERIENCE

From NOV/2022 to present (Bogotá D.C. - Colombia)

Teleperformance

Data Specialist

Tasks: Tasked with overseeing the development of new databases and monitoring database performance. Responsible for collating and verifying data from multiple sources, assisting with the implementation of data software storage systems, and executing data transfers using Python.

Main tools: Python, SQL and Excel.

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/company/teleperformance/

From MAR/2022 to NOV/2022 (Bogotá D.C. - Colombia)

Pidgin Contact Solutions

Python Developer

Tasks: In charge of task automation by means of RPA's for data extraction and manipulation with Python. Besides, responsible of debugging tasks of form and efficiency.

Main packages: Selenium WebDriver and Pandas.

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/company/pidgincontactsolutions/mycompany/ From AUG/2021 to present (Bogotá D.C. - Colombia)

FreeLancer

Tasks: In charge of providing solutions for the projects entrusted. For example: Web design, statistical reports, API design, etc.

Main packages: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Django, JavaScript and Bootstrap.

EDUCATION

2018 to present **Degree: Mathematician aspirant**

Bogotá D.C. National University of

Colombia Colombia

2017 Degree: Academic Bachelor Liceo of Cervantes Augustinian Bogotá D.C.

Colombia Priests

CERTIFICATES

2022 **Python Specialization**

Bogotá D.C. Colombia

Michigan University (United States)

Courses

- 1. Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)
- 2. Python Data Structures
- 3. Using Python to Access Web Data
- 4. Using Databases with Python
- 5. Capstone: Retrieving, Processing, and Visualizing Data with Python

2022 Introduction to control versioning with Bogotá D.C. Git and GitHub

Colombia

Andes University (Colombia)

2021 Software Development Diploma

Bogotá D.C. North University (Colombia) Colombia

2021 **Programing Fundamentals Diploma**

Bogotá D.C. North University (Colombia) Colombia

2021 **Basic Programming Diploma** Bogotá D.C. North University (Colombia)

Colombia

SKILLS

Python NumPy

> Pandas Matplotlib Scipy Flask **FastAPI**

Selenium

Web development HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript Bootstrap

Databases SQL

> MySQL PostgreSQL

Other \mathbb{C}^{++}

> LaTeX Git

REFERENCES

Personal references:

Name: Juan Lucas Ibarra Sierra.

Phone: 3213438944

E-mail: <u>juanlucas2000@hotmail.com</u> **Occupation:** Engineer at Endava.

Name: Nicolas Eduardo Gutierrez Meza.

Phone: 3013833841

E-mail: <u>nicolas.Gutierrez@co.ey.com</u> **Occupation:** Staff - IT Consultant at EY.

Work references:

Name: Asley Nicole Mora.

Relationship: Pidgin contact solutions

manager.

Phone: 3053194579

E-mail: nmora@pidgin.com.co

Name: Nelson Reales Herrera.

Relationship: Teleperformance's RPA

Supervisor.

Phone: 3023237198

E-mail:

realesherrera.5@nlsa.teleperformance.com